<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/flanaess-fables/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/flanaess-fables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-08T13:51:24-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Flanaess Fables | Adventures of wandering Oerthlings</title><subtitle>Welcome Oerthlings! Follow the story of our wandering Oerthlings as they adventure across the Flanaess.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Zethlentyn, the grand city of the Drow</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/10/01/welcome-to-zethlentyn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Zethlentyn, the grand city of the Drow" /><published>2020-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/10/01/welcome-to-zethlentyn</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/10/01/welcome-to-zethlentyn.html">Several weeks have passed since our heroes freed the hamlet of Durhlong from its devil-may-care deity. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On the road to Zethlentyn, the party was ambushed by a group of elder bulettes and things looked grim as Scutters and Jer’amy went down for the count. Clever tactics by Aldon and Dreggard kept them all in the land of the living, and the only surviving bulette fled. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Arriving in the grand city of the Drow, the group hired a noble lady to guide them around. They met with the head of house Do’Urden who revealed her role as leader of the Celestilites. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The band of explorers decided to spend some time in Zethlentyn (or Z-town as Westin has dubbed it). Dreggard stayed very busy, splitting his time in between the Lizard racetrack with Aldon and the menagerie with Sanzac. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Little is known about how Jer’amy spent his time, Westin tried to tag along with him but was sternly told to mind his own business. Dejected, Westin decided to ease the pain by purchasing himself a fancy hand crossbow, he has been wearing it proudly on his back ever since. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party did notice that Jer’amy walked into the Sun Slave a few mornings ago looking slightly sick. He was staggering a bit and rubbing his eyes frequently.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Several weeks have passed since our heroes freed the hamlet of Durhlong from its devil-may-care deity. On the road to Zethlentyn, the party was ambushed by a group of elder bulettes and things looked grim as Scutters and Jer’amy went down for the count. Clever tactics by Aldon and Dreggard kept them all in the land of the living, and the only surviving bulette fled. Arriving in the grand city of the Drow, the group hired a noble lady to guide them around. They met with the head of house Do’Urden who revealed her role as leader of the Celestilites. The band of explorers decided to spend some time in Zethlentyn (or Z-town as Westin has dubbed it). Dreggard stayed very busy, splitting his time in between the Lizard racetrack with Aldon and the menagerie with Sanzac. Little is known about how Jer’amy spent his time, Westin tried to tag along with him but was sternly told to mind his own business. Dejected, Westin decided to ease the pain by purchasing himself a fancy hand crossbow, he has been wearing it proudly on his back ever since. The party did notice that Jer’amy walked into the Sun Slave a few mornings ago looking slightly sick. He was staggering a bit and rubbing his eyes frequently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rage of Sanzac the Slithery &amp;amp; Cirederill’s demise</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/24/sanzac-the-slithery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rage of Sanzac the Slithery &amp;amp; Cirederill’s demise" /><published>2020-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/24/sanzac-the-slithery</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/24/sanzac-the-slithery.html">The sleepy squad was led against their will to the Cliffwatch where Cirederill spoke briefly before forcing them to plunge into the dark lake below. The heroes did not dive gracefully and the sound of flesh slapping against water was painful to the ears. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;    
Only &lt;strong&gt;Sanzac the Slithery&lt;/strong&gt;, who had been carried in a tube, avoided a most embarrassing encounter with the water. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The surprises didn’t stop there - our team learned that Lliar’ryathoss had grown averse to a life of dominating weaker beings and had chosen a new name and path. He asked his guests to help free him of his bond to the city by any means possible. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is when Sanzac’s eyes started to sizzle, furious at Cirederill for her deception. He stormed out of the lair and began climbing the cliffs while the others were given the ability to fly. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac caused the Cliffwatch to erupt before his companions had a chance to reason with him. Many cultists were instantly downed, but Cirederill escaped into her temple where Aldon watched her moves silently. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Eventually the dauntless druid was convinced by Jer’amy to settle down and carried off by the town guard who were less than pleased with his behavior. While he cooled off in a holding cell, Jer’amy schemed with the leader of Durhlong to put an end to the abductions and initiations led by the cult of Lliar’ryathoss.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jacqueline was convinced and helped devise a plan. Cirederill was summoned to Jacqueline’s office where she found a bit more than she bargained for as a Barlgura ripped into her chest and feasted upon her flesh. The Cultists were thereafter convinced to pursue a new lifestyle and Sanzac was convinced that this pathetic cell would not hold him for long...</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The sleepy squad was led against their will to the Cliffwatch where Cirederill spoke briefly before forcing them to plunge into the dark lake below. The heroes did not dive gracefully and the sound of flesh slapping against water was painful to the ears. Only Sanzac the Slithery, who had been carried in a tube, avoided a most embarrassing encounter with the water. The surprises didn’t stop there - our team learned that Lliar’ryathoss had grown averse to a life of dominating weaker beings and had chosen a new name and path. He asked his guests to help free him of his bond to the city by any means possible. This is when Sanzac’s eyes started to sizzle, furious at Cirederill for her deception. He stormed out of the lair and began climbing the cliffs while the others were given the ability to fly. Sanzac caused the Cliffwatch to erupt before his companions had a chance to reason with him. Many cultists were instantly downed, but Cirederill escaped into her temple where Aldon watched her moves silently. Eventually the dauntless druid was convinced by Jer’amy to settle down and carried off by the town guard who were less than pleased with his behavior. While he cooled off in a holding cell, Jer’amy schemed with the leader of Durhlong to put an end to the abductions and initiations led by the cult of Lliar’ryathoss. Jacqueline was convinced and helped devise a plan. Cirederill was summoned to Jacqueline’s office where she found a bit more than she bargained for as a Barlgura ripped into her chest and feasted upon her flesh. The Cultists were thereafter convinced to pursue a new lifestyle and Sanzac was convinced that this pathetic cell would not hold him for long...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poison pools crossing amid the clutches of monstrosities</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/17/poison-pool-crossing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poison pools crossing amid the clutches of monstrosities" /><published>2020-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/17/poison-pool-crossing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/17/poison-pool-crossing.html">The voyage through the Underdark continued as the group found themselves once again faced with the challenge of crossing the poison pools. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon decided to make use of his new arachnid abilities, scaling the cavern walls. Westin and Dreggard stumbled into the green goo and were attacked by an ancient guardian. With Dreggard in its clutches, the ancient guardian began to sink into the depths. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac, realizing poison pools weren’t Dreggard’s favored terrain, pulled him onto a nearby rock. But his safety was only temporary... a second monstrosity grappled his paralyzed body and tried to escape but Tazolil pierced it’s brain through with his short sword. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After clearing the pools, the hardy bunch found their way to Draenoss’ stalagmite tower and uncovered some valuable items for their journey. They carefully avoided some magical traps set to dissuade sticky fingers. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Caught up in the thrill of the hunt, the team neglected to notice that Tazolil had given them the slip, heading back to Tyrybblyn. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard charmed a couple of Rothe into taking the Drow’s place while Jer’amy acted on a telepathic prompt from a mysterious being. He led the crew to the well defended hamlet of Durhlong where they met some interesting characters. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
They searched for the source of the message but their questions only created more questions. They were left with a strange feeling in the pit of their stomachs after visiting with the town religious leader, Cirederill. She offered to initiate them into the order of Lliar’ryathoss’ faithful with a promise of power if they were deemed worthy. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Eventually the party retired to their quarters to study some of the manuscripts discovered earlier at the wizard’s tower. Sleep and a deep trance slowly overtook them that night - even Jer’amy who had been in the habit of not sleeping at all. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The last thing they remembered was an odd smell followed by a hazy vapor creeping through the closed door.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The voyage through the Underdark continued as the group found themselves once again faced with the challenge of crossing the poison pools. Aldon decided to make use of his new arachnid abilities, scaling the cavern walls. Westin and Dreggard stumbled into the green goo and were attacked by an ancient guardian. With Dreggard in its clutches, the ancient guardian began to sink into the depths. Sanzac, realizing poison pools weren’t Dreggard’s favored terrain, pulled him onto a nearby rock. But his safety was only temporary... a second monstrosity grappled his paralyzed body and tried to escape but Tazolil pierced it’s brain through with his short sword. After clearing the pools, the hardy bunch found their way to Draenoss’ stalagmite tower and uncovered some valuable items for their journey. They carefully avoided some magical traps set to dissuade sticky fingers. Caught up in the thrill of the hunt, the team neglected to notice that Tazolil had given them the slip, heading back to Tyrybblyn. Dreggard charmed a couple of Rothe into taking the Drow’s place while Jer’amy acted on a telepathic prompt from a mysterious being. He led the crew to the well defended hamlet of Durhlong where they met some interesting characters. They searched for the source of the message but their questions only created more questions. They were left with a strange feeling in the pit of their stomachs after visiting with the town religious leader, Cirederill. She offered to initiate them into the order of Lliar’ryathoss’ faithful with a promise of power if they were deemed worthy. Eventually the party retired to their quarters to study some of the manuscripts discovered earlier at the wizard’s tower. Sleep and a deep trance slowly overtook them that night - even Jer’amy who had been in the habit of not sleeping at all. The last thing they remembered was an odd smell followed by a hazy vapor creeping through the closed door.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A betrayal worth a mine of Godsdream</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A betrayal worth a mine of Godsdream" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream.html">Our team of rugged adventurers were startled when a Minotaur began questioning their choice of traveling companions. She left them with a warning about the Drow and also the Duergar. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy noted a change in Draenoss’ behavior as they drew closer and closer to their prize. Westin discovered the Duergar mine site ahead, which brought a tiny bit of warmth to Aldon’s cold, dead heart. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon tried to negotiate with the dark dwarves but could not find common ground and fighting broke out. Sanzac shook things up causing rocks to bury multiple enemies, but Dreggard was caught up as well. Aldon had mercy on a Duergar hammerer who was trapped inside a machine. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After defeating the Duergar, nothing stood in the way of Draenoss and his Godsdream, nothing except our lovable band of heroes!!! 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Draenoss turned on the party and introduced them to his ally named Marwenye who promptly unleashed an insect plague upon them. Sanzac had a bit of an identity crisis, changing from bear, to yuan-ti, to snake - eventually grappling the old drow. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon fired an arrow through a swarm of locusts, surprising Draenoss and dropping him to the ground. The team rallied against Marwenye who called a demon to her aid. Tazolil came to the aid of the party and ran the old fossil through with his shortsword. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And so, the Godsdream fell into the hands of the Underdark Voyagers.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Our team of rugged adventurers were startled when a Minotaur began questioning their choice of traveling companions. She left them with a warning about the Drow and also the Duergar. Jer’amy noted a change in Draenoss’ behavior as they drew closer and closer to their prize. Westin discovered the Duergar mine site ahead, which brought a tiny bit of warmth to Aldon’s cold, dead heart. Aldon tried to negotiate with the dark dwarves but could not find common ground and fighting broke out. Sanzac shook things up causing rocks to bury multiple enemies, but Dreggard was caught up as well. Aldon had mercy on a Duergar hammerer who was trapped inside a machine. After defeating the Duergar, nothing stood in the way of Draenoss and his Godsdream, nothing except our lovable band of heroes!!! Draenoss turned on the party and introduced them to his ally named Marwenye who promptly unleashed an insect plague upon them. Sanzac had a bit of an identity crisis, changing from bear, to yuan-ti, to snake - eventually grappling the old drow. Aldon fired an arrow through a swarm of locusts, surprising Draenoss and dropping him to the ground. The team rallied against Marwenye who called a demon to her aid. Tazolil came to the aid of the party and ran the old fossil through with his shortsword. And so, the Godsdream fell into the hands of the Underdark Voyagers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scutters the Unshakeable &amp;amp; the lair of a slithering creature</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scutters the Unshakeable &amp;amp; the lair of a slithering creature" /><published>2020-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable.html">Westin scurried ahead of the party across an ominous stone bridge while Draenoss brought up the rear. A group of Stirges was awoken as Scutters &amp; Sanzac sent stones tumbling into the abyss. Dreggard and Jer’amy suffered bites but maintained their footing on the bridge. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After the bridge, the mighty adventurers entered what appeared to be the lair of a slithering creature. Aldon’s complexion reached a new level of pale as images of purple worms filled his mind. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard found a treasure trove while Tazolil and Westin found themselves in the midst of a rockslide. Archie scouted a large room and reported danger ahead. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Battle commenced against two Grick Alphas who seemed to be working together with an ancient Roper. Draenoss, Sanzac and Dreggard all felt the terrifying touch of the monster’s tendrils, their blood served as tribute to the beast, who was eventually felled by a vicious bite from &lt;strong&gt;Scutters the Unshakeable&lt;/strong&gt;. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Next up in the perilous journey was a room fool of poison pools. Sanzac lost his footing, receiving some acid damage on his leg while Jer’amy, not to be bested, essentially cannon-balled into the depths. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party eventually made their way to a much more hospitable set of pools, crystal clear and cool to the touch. They were enjoying some water therapy when a voice from above interrupted “Enjoying your dip, I take it?”</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Westin scurried ahead of the party across an ominous stone bridge while Draenoss brought up the rear. A group of Stirges was awoken as Scutters &amp; Sanzac sent stones tumbling into the abyss. Dreggard and Jer’amy suffered bites but maintained their footing on the bridge. After the bridge, the mighty adventurers entered what appeared to be the lair of a slithering creature. Aldon’s complexion reached a new level of pale as images of purple worms filled his mind. Dreggard found a treasure trove while Tazolil and Westin found themselves in the midst of a rockslide. Archie scouted a large room and reported danger ahead. Battle commenced against two Grick Alphas who seemed to be working together with an ancient Roper. Draenoss, Sanzac and Dreggard all felt the terrifying touch of the monster’s tendrils, their blood served as tribute to the beast, who was eventually felled by a vicious bite from Scutters the Unshakeable. Next up in the perilous journey was a room fool of poison pools. Sanzac lost his footing, receiving some acid damage on his leg while Jer’amy, not to be bested, essentially cannon-balled into the depths. The party eventually made their way to a much more hospitable set of pools, crystal clear and cool to the touch. They were enjoying some water therapy when a voice from above interrupted “Enjoying your dip, I take it?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zeerith’s ingredients &amp;amp; Draenoss’ promise</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zeerith’s ingredients &amp;amp; Draenoss’ promise" /><published>2020-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients.html">The Underdark Initiates leapt at the chance to spend a bit of time on the surface, they scaled a mighty series of stairs which led them to a place Dreggard, or Stray, once called home.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
He was reacquainted with a hungry honey badger who led them all to Gordra the Druid.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Gordra had mostly disappointing news to share on the state of the forest. According to him, excursions were continuing at an alarming rate.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The crew set themselves to the task of collecting the ingredients needed by Zeerith the barkeep.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard briefly contracted poison ivy, while Jer’amy had a flashback to Cheryl the Steeder after a snake pounced at his tushy.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Westin awoke an ancient Treant by climbing it’s branches.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Having gathered most of the supplies, the party split up, Aldon and Westin headed back to collect payment while the others made plans to scout the work camp.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac infiltrated the camp in the form of a mouse and discovered the laborers were extracting oil from the lake.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Late in the night, the party was ambushed by an Orc patrol, but the Orcs quickly realized they picked the wrong adventurers to meddle with.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After all had returned to the tavern, Jer’amy was confronted by a barbed devil and left to take care of some ‘business’.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard convinced Aldon to take on the hot wing challenge at the bazaar only to set themselves and their surroundings ablaze. Jer’amy returned and cleaned up the remaining wings, licking his fingers dry.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tazolil met back up with the group and they set off for the city of Zethlentyn. Not long after departing, they came across an exiled mage named Draenoss who resided in an enormous stalagmite tower.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Draenoss pleaded for assistance in obtaining a mineral called Godsdream – promising to enchant the gear of each member of the party as a reward.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It was decided that this quest was a worthy one, and our heroes tightened their belts and made ready to begin!</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The Underdark Initiates leapt at the chance to spend a bit of time on the surface, they scaled a mighty series of stairs which led them to a place Dreggard, or Stray, once called home. He was reacquainted with a hungry honey badger who led them all to Gordra the Druid. Gordra had mostly disappointing news to share on the state of the forest. According to him, excursions were continuing at an alarming rate. The crew set themselves to the task of collecting the ingredients needed by Zeerith the barkeep. Dreggard briefly contracted poison ivy, while Jer’amy had a flashback to Cheryl the Steeder after a snake pounced at his tushy. Westin awoke an ancient Treant by climbing it’s branches. Having gathered most of the supplies, the party split up, Aldon and Westin headed back to collect payment while the others made plans to scout the work camp. Sanzac infiltrated the camp in the form of a mouse and discovered the laborers were extracting oil from the lake. Late in the night, the party was ambushed by an Orc patrol, but the Orcs quickly realized they picked the wrong adventurers to meddle with. After all had returned to the tavern, Jer’amy was confronted by a barbed devil and left to take care of some ‘business’. Dreggard convinced Aldon to take on the hot wing challenge at the bazaar only to set themselves and their surroundings ablaze. Jer’amy returned and cleaned up the remaining wings, licking his fingers dry. Tazolil met back up with the group and they set off for the city of Zethlentyn. Not long after departing, they came across an exiled mage named Draenoss who resided in an enormous stalagmite tower. Draenoss pleaded for assistance in obtaining a mineral called Godsdream – promising to enchant the gear of each member of the party as a reward. It was decided that this quest was a worthy one, and our heroes tightened their belts and made ready to begin!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vampires, zombies &amp;amp; burning cobweb</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vampires, zombies &amp;amp; burning cobweb" /><published>2020-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs.html">The fireworks began when Jer’amy sent a couple green blasts towards a group of zombies and vampires who were out for the blood of a Svirfneblin caravan.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac laid down the mighty moonbeam, while Aldon heated things up.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard spawned an expanse of poky scratchies, and on top of it all, Westin stood ready to unleash a makeshift battering ram.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The zombies blazed forward into the fray while the vampires climbed around walls covered with flaming spiderwebs. Those who were lucky enough to advance through the obstacles were pelted by darts and bolts.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An ancient Vampire managed to close in on Jer’amy and grab hold of his wrinkly flesh, but in a flash, Jer’amy popped out of harm’s way. Without a victim to feed upon, the vampire tried to flee, but was trapped by the moonbeam and destroyed with a stake to the heart.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
At this point, Westin rushed in with blade in hand towards a Vampire Spawn who was quickly approaching. The party looked on in shock as the two clashed and not one, but two bites were exchanged.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In the end, the Vampires were felled and the Svirfneblin were saved.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The adventurers continued on their way to Tyrybblyn.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Upon arrival, they were led to the headquarters of House Claddatar and accepted their reward for delivering the treacherous merchant Zim. They also accepted a courier mission, delivering Celestilite schematics to Zethlentyn.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We find our heroes at the Slaughtered Star, preparing for a journey to the surface.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The fireworks began when Jer’amy sent a couple green blasts towards a group of zombies and vampires who were out for the blood of a Svirfneblin caravan. Sanzac laid down the mighty moonbeam, while Aldon heated things up. Dreggard spawned an expanse of poky scratchies, and on top of it all, Westin stood ready to unleash a makeshift battering ram. The zombies blazed forward into the fray while the vampires climbed around walls covered with flaming spiderwebs. Those who were lucky enough to advance through the obstacles were pelted by darts and bolts. An ancient Vampire managed to close in on Jer’amy and grab hold of his wrinkly flesh, but in a flash, Jer’amy popped out of harm’s way. Without a victim to feed upon, the vampire tried to flee, but was trapped by the moonbeam and destroyed with a stake to the heart. At this point, Westin rushed in with blade in hand towards a Vampire Spawn who was quickly approaching. The party looked on in shock as the two clashed and not one, but two bites were exchanged. In the end, the Vampires were felled and the Svirfneblin were saved. The adventurers continued on their way to Tyrybblyn. Upon arrival, they were led to the headquarters of House Claddatar and accepted their reward for delivering the treacherous merchant Zim. They also accepted a courier mission, delivering Celestilite schematics to Zethlentyn. We find our heroes at the Slaughtered Star, preparing for a journey to the surface.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mystery of Von Zim’s wares</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mystery of Von Zim’s wares" /><published>2020-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim.html">Sanzac led the way back to Zim’s caravan where the party was asked to help investigate some disappearances from Zim’s wares. The crew put on their detective hats and began sniffing for clues.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon began by subtly hinting at the missing items with the Drow while Jer’amy got to know Nora, Aaron and Haleth better. Dreggard found Brendan practicing some martial moves and showed him a few moves of his own.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A lead suspect was yet to emerge, so Aldon decided to take a more direct approach. He searched Dinnozz’s bag while he slept and found the missing items. Zim was alerted and decided to confront the issue.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dinnozz denied all claims and was enraged at the accusation. He drew his blade as the adventurers tried to mediate. Dreggard only exacerbated the issue and became a target for Dinnozz’s frustration.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A battle began and one of the Steeder’s joined the Drow cause, biting deep into Jer’amy’s hindquarters. Heavily outnumbered, the Drow were defeated but not killed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Zim stared on in shock and Jer’amy noticed a hint of guilt in his eyes. Zim confessed that he planted the items in Dinnozz’s bag. Rhys convinced the party to continue on to Tyrybblyn with Zim locked up in a cart.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not long after, voices were heard in the tunnels ahead. A caravan of Svirfneblin were preparing for a vampire attack, they offered their materials to help build up defenses and Dreggard used his knowledge of nature and survival to devise a plan.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Sanzac led the way back to Zim’s caravan where the party was asked to help investigate some disappearances from Zim’s wares. The crew put on their detective hats and began sniffing for clues. Aldon began by subtly hinting at the missing items with the Drow while Jer’amy got to know Nora, Aaron and Haleth better. Dreggard found Brendan practicing some martial moves and showed him a few moves of his own. A lead suspect was yet to emerge, so Aldon decided to take a more direct approach. He searched Dinnozz’s bag while he slept and found the missing items. Zim was alerted and decided to confront the issue. Dinnozz denied all claims and was enraged at the accusation. He drew his blade as the adventurers tried to mediate. Dreggard only exacerbated the issue and became a target for Dinnozz’s frustration. A battle began and one of the Steeder’s joined the Drow cause, biting deep into Jer’amy’s hindquarters. Heavily outnumbered, the Drow were defeated but not killed. Zim stared on in shock and Jer’amy noticed a hint of guilt in his eyes. Zim confessed that he planted the items in Dinnozz’s bag. Rhys convinced the party to continue on to Tyrybblyn with Zim locked up in a cart. Not long after, voices were heard in the tunnels ahead. A caravan of Svirfneblin were preparing for a vampire attack, they offered their materials to help build up defenses and Dreggard used his knowledge of nature and survival to devise a plan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A fledgling Drow in distress</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A fledgling Drow in distress" /><published>2020-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow.html">Our epic saga continues with a Drow in distress, stuck in a massive spider web. Zim urged the caravan to move on, but the adventurers found it in their hearts to escort the entangled child to her family.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The distance was not great, but the mission proved to be quite eventful. Jer’amy triggered two glyphs that were set to ward off intruders, while Dreggard found himself slowed by a massive stone golem.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac disarmed the stone golem, aided by a recollection from the young Drow. The party snuck through a room of trickster mushrooms, then the air became cold.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party had stumbled upon a haunted farmhouse where several undead lay in wait. The terrifying visage of a ghost shook the resolve of the mighty challengers, all except Scutters the Unshakeable!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac brought light to the darkness, burning the undead into non-existence. It was then, that a Drow hunting party, on the lookout for their kin, found the heroes.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party peacefully exchanged the Drow child for some well deserved time in a restorative hot springs.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On their return to the main tunnels, they were ambushed by Hobgoblin bandits, demanding Dreggard’s magical battle axe. Sanzac opted for action over diplomacy and created a mighty eruption under their feet.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Soon after, Jer’amy added acid and cold damage to the fold, and howls could be heard from the black pit.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One bandit managed to escape, but not for long.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac hunted him down and after a fierce battle, the heroes emerged victorious, and Westin gained a new coin purse.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Our epic saga continues with a Drow in distress, stuck in a massive spider web. Zim urged the caravan to move on, but the adventurers found it in their hearts to escort the entangled child to her family. The distance was not great, but the mission proved to be quite eventful. Jer’amy triggered two glyphs that were set to ward off intruders, while Dreggard found himself slowed by a massive stone golem. Sanzac disarmed the stone golem, aided by a recollection from the young Drow. The party snuck through a room of trickster mushrooms, then the air became cold. The party had stumbled upon a haunted farmhouse where several undead lay in wait. The terrifying visage of a ghost shook the resolve of the mighty challengers, all except Scutters the Unshakeable! Sanzac brought light to the darkness, burning the undead into non-existence. It was then, that a Drow hunting party, on the lookout for their kin, found the heroes. The party peacefully exchanged the Drow child for some well deserved time in a restorative hot springs. On their return to the main tunnels, they were ambushed by Hobgoblin bandits, demanding Dreggard’s magical battle axe. Sanzac opted for action over diplomacy and created a mighty eruption under their feet. Soon after, Jer’amy added acid and cold damage to the fold, and howls could be heard from the black pit. One bandit managed to escape, but not for long. Sanzac hunted him down and after a fierce battle, the heroes emerged victorious, and Westin gained a new coin purse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Underdark initiates</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Underdark initiates" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates.html">Bidding farewell to Stoneheim, the group met with Zim and his ‘Von Zeam Team’. They delved deep under the surface and began their journey through the underdark.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy earned the respect of Nora, the she-dwarf, while Aldon had a little fun with the rearguard’s rears. Zim told some stories and morale was high until a faulty wheel slowed the caravan to a halt and Jer’amy felt compelled to investigate a strange energy in a side tunnel.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The tunnel led to a source of ancient magic which caught our courageous friends in a time loop with a delusional mage and a frisky Gynosphinx.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Both physical and mental faculties were strained as the Gynosphinx challenged the party to answer her riddles in order to be allowed to escape.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After successfully answering, the party tried to also negotiate the release of Gunther the mage, but Persemone the sphinx was too attached to him.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Returning to the carts, the party pondered the possibility of time travel and how they could have done things differently in the past.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not long after their return, a pack of Ankhegs ambushed the VZT (Von Zeam Team). Aaron was snatched up in the vicious mandibles of an Ankheg as it began to burrow underground, but Sanzac’s heroics saved his life.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Slightly bloodied, but still on their feet, the caravan rested and once again, felt new powers surging into their bodies.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Bidding farewell to Stoneheim, the group met with Zim and his ‘Von Zeam Team’. They delved deep under the surface and began their journey through the underdark. Jer’amy earned the respect of Nora, the she-dwarf, while Aldon had a little fun with the rearguard’s rears. Zim told some stories and morale was high until a faulty wheel slowed the caravan to a halt and Jer’amy felt compelled to investigate a strange energy in a side tunnel. The tunnel led to a source of ancient magic which caught our courageous friends in a time loop with a delusional mage and a frisky Gynosphinx. Both physical and mental faculties were strained as the Gynosphinx challenged the party to answer her riddles in order to be allowed to escape. After successfully answering, the party tried to also negotiate the release of Gunther the mage, but Persemone the sphinx was too attached to him. Returning to the carts, the party pondered the possibility of time travel and how they could have done things differently in the past. Not long after their return, a pack of Ankhegs ambushed the VZT (Von Zeam Team). Aaron was snatched up in the vicious mandibles of an Ankheg as it began to burrow underground, but Sanzac’s heroics saved his life. Slightly bloodied, but still on their feet, the caravan rested and once again, felt new powers surging into their bodies.</summary></entry></feed>