<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/flanaess-fables/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/flanaess-fables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-05T20:07:07-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Flanaess Fables | Adventures of wandering Oerthlings</title><subtitle>Welcome Oerthlings! Follow the story of our wandering Oerthlings as they adventure across the Flanaess.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A betrayal worth a mine of Godsdream</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A betrayal worth a mine of Godsdream" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/10/betrayal-worth-a-mine-of-godsdream.html">Our team of rugged adventurers were startled when a Minotaur began questioning their choice of traveling companions. She left them with a warning about the Drow and also the Duergar. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy noted a change in Draenoss’ behavior as they drew closer and closer to their prize. Westin discovered the Duergar mine site ahead, which brought a tiny bit of warmth to Aldon’s cold, dead heart. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon tried to negotiate with the dark dwarves but could not find common ground and fighting broke out. Sanzac shook things up causing rocks to bury multiple enemies, but Dreggard was caught up as well. Aldon had mercy on a Duergar hammerer who was trapped inside a machine. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After defeating the Duergar, nothing stood in the way of Draenoss and his Godsdream, nothing except our lovable band of heroes!!! 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Draenoss turned on the party and introduced them to his ally named Marwenye who promptly unleashed an insect plague upon them. Sanzac had a bit of an identity crisis, changing from bear, to yuan-ti, to snake - eventually grappling the old drow. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon fired an arrow through a swarm of locusts, surprising Draenoss and dropping him to the ground. The team rallied against Marwenye who called a demon to her aid. Tazolil came to the aid of the party and ran the old fossil through with his shortsword. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And so, the Godsdream fell into the hands of the Underdark Voyagers.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Our team of rugged adventurers were startled when a Minotaur began questioning their choice of traveling companions. She left them with a warning about the Drow and also the Duergar. Jer’amy noted a change in Draenoss’ behavior as they drew closer and closer to their prize. Westin discovered the Duergar mine site ahead, which brought a tiny bit of warmth to Aldon’s cold, dead heart. Aldon tried to negotiate with the dark dwarves but could not find common ground and fighting broke out. Sanzac shook things up causing rocks to bury multiple enemies, but Dreggard was caught up as well. Aldon had mercy on a Duergar hammerer who was trapped inside a machine. After defeating the Duergar, nothing stood in the way of Draenoss and his Godsdream, nothing except our lovable band of heroes!!! Draenoss turned on the party and introduced them to his ally named Marwenye who promptly unleashed an insect plague upon them. Sanzac had a bit of an identity crisis, changing from bear, to yuan-ti, to snake - eventually grappling the old drow. Aldon fired an arrow through a swarm of locusts, surprising Draenoss and dropping him to the ground. The team rallied against Marwenye who called a demon to her aid. Tazolil came to the aid of the party and ran the old fossil through with his shortsword. And so, the Godsdream fell into the hands of the Underdark Voyagers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scutters the Unshakeable &amp;amp; the lair of a slithering creature</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scutters the Unshakeable &amp;amp; the lair of a slithering creature" /><published>2020-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/09/03/scutters-the-unshakeable.html">Westin scurried ahead of the party across an ominous stone bridge while Draenoss brought up the rear. A group of Stirges was awoken as Scutters &amp; Sanzac sent stones tumbling into the abyss. Dreggard and Jer’amy suffered bites but maintained their footing on the bridge. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After the bridge, the mighty adventurers entered what appeared to be the lair of a slithering creature. Aldon’s complexion reached a new level of pale as images of purple worms filled his mind. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard found a treasure trove while Tazolil and Westin found themselves in the midst of a rockslide. Archie scouted a large room and reported danger ahead. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Battle commenced against two Grick Alphas who seemed to be working together with an ancient Roper. Draenoss, Sanzac and Dreggard all felt the terrifying touch of the monster’s tendrils, their blood served as tribute to the beast, who was eventually felled by a vicious bite from &lt;strong&gt;Scutters the Unshakeable&lt;/strong&gt;. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Next up in the perilous journey was a room fool of poison pools. Sanzac lost his footing, receiving some acid damage on his leg while Jer’amy, not to be bested, essentially cannon-balled into the depths. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party eventually made their way to a much more hospitable set of pools, crystal clear and cool to the touch. They were enjoying some water therapy when a voice from above interrupted “Enjoying your dip, I take it?”</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Westin scurried ahead of the party across an ominous stone bridge while Draenoss brought up the rear. A group of Stirges was awoken as Scutters &amp; Sanzac sent stones tumbling into the abyss. Dreggard and Jer’amy suffered bites but maintained their footing on the bridge. After the bridge, the mighty adventurers entered what appeared to be the lair of a slithering creature. Aldon’s complexion reached a new level of pale as images of purple worms filled his mind. Dreggard found a treasure trove while Tazolil and Westin found themselves in the midst of a rockslide. Archie scouted a large room and reported danger ahead. Battle commenced against two Grick Alphas who seemed to be working together with an ancient Roper. Draenoss, Sanzac and Dreggard all felt the terrifying touch of the monster’s tendrils, their blood served as tribute to the beast, who was eventually felled by a vicious bite from Scutters the Unshakeable. Next up in the perilous journey was a room fool of poison pools. Sanzac lost his footing, receiving some acid damage on his leg while Jer’amy, not to be bested, essentially cannon-balled into the depths. The party eventually made their way to a much more hospitable set of pools, crystal clear and cool to the touch. They were enjoying some water therapy when a voice from above interrupted “Enjoying your dip, I take it?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zeerith’s ingredients &amp;amp; Draenoss’ promise</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zeerith’s ingredients &amp;amp; Draenoss’ promise" /><published>2020-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/27/zeeriths-ingredients.html">The Underdark Initiates leapt at the chance to spend a bit of time on the surface, they scaled a mighty series of stairs which led them to a place Dreggard, or Stray, once called home.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
He was reacquainted with a hungry honey badger who led them all to Gordra the Druid.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Gordra had mostly disappointing news to share on the state of the forest. According to him, excursions were continuing at an alarming rate.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The crew set themselves to the task of collecting the ingredients needed by Zeerith the barkeep.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard briefly contracted poison ivy, while Jer’amy had a flashback to Cheryl the Steeder after a snake pounced at his tushy.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Westin awoke an ancient Treant by climbing it’s branches.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Having gathered most of the supplies, the party split up, Aldon and Westin headed back to collect payment while the others made plans to scout the work camp.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac infiltrated the camp in the form of a mouse and discovered the laborers were extracting oil from the lake.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Late in the night, the party was ambushed by an Orc patrol, but the Orcs quickly realized they picked the wrong adventurers to meddle with.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After all had returned to the tavern, Jer’amy was confronted by a barbed devil and left to take care of some ‘business’.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard convinced Aldon to take on the hot wing challenge at the bazaar only to set themselves and their surroundings ablaze. Jer’amy returned and cleaned up the remaining wings, licking his fingers dry.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tazolil met back up with the group and they set off for the city of Zethlentyn. Not long after departing, they came across an exiled mage named Draenoss who resided in an enormous stalagmite tower.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Draenoss pleaded for assistance in obtaining a mineral called Godsdream – promising to enchant the gear of each member of the party as a reward.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It was decided that this quest was a worthy one, and our heroes tightened their belts and made ready to begin!</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The Underdark Initiates leapt at the chance to spend a bit of time on the surface, they scaled a mighty series of stairs which led them to a place Dreggard, or Stray, once called home. He was reacquainted with a hungry honey badger who led them all to Gordra the Druid. Gordra had mostly disappointing news to share on the state of the forest. According to him, excursions were continuing at an alarming rate. The crew set themselves to the task of collecting the ingredients needed by Zeerith the barkeep. Dreggard briefly contracted poison ivy, while Jer’amy had a flashback to Cheryl the Steeder after a snake pounced at his tushy. Westin awoke an ancient Treant by climbing it’s branches. Having gathered most of the supplies, the party split up, Aldon and Westin headed back to collect payment while the others made plans to scout the work camp. Sanzac infiltrated the camp in the form of a mouse and discovered the laborers were extracting oil from the lake. Late in the night, the party was ambushed by an Orc patrol, but the Orcs quickly realized they picked the wrong adventurers to meddle with. After all had returned to the tavern, Jer’amy was confronted by a barbed devil and left to take care of some ‘business’. Dreggard convinced Aldon to take on the hot wing challenge at the bazaar only to set themselves and their surroundings ablaze. Jer’amy returned and cleaned up the remaining wings, licking his fingers dry. Tazolil met back up with the group and they set off for the city of Zethlentyn. Not long after departing, they came across an exiled mage named Draenoss who resided in an enormous stalagmite tower. Draenoss pleaded for assistance in obtaining a mineral called Godsdream – promising to enchant the gear of each member of the party as a reward. It was decided that this quest was a worthy one, and our heroes tightened their belts and made ready to begin!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vampires, zombies &amp;amp; burning cobweb</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vampires, zombies &amp;amp; burning cobweb" /><published>2020-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/20/vampires-zombies-webs.html">The fireworks began when Jer’amy sent a couple green blasts towards a group of zombies and vampires who were out for the blood of a Svirfneblin caravan.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac laid down the mighty moonbeam, while Aldon heated things up.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard spawned an expanse of poky scratchies, and on top of it all, Westin stood ready to unleash a makeshift battering ram.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The zombies blazed forward into the fray while the vampires climbed around walls covered with flaming spiderwebs. Those who were lucky enough to advance through the obstacles were pelted by darts and bolts.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An ancient Vampire managed to close in on Jer’amy and grab hold of his wrinkly flesh, but in a flash, Jer’amy popped out of harm’s way. Without a victim to feed upon, the vampire tried to flee, but was trapped by the moonbeam and destroyed with a stake to the heart.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
At this point, Westin rushed in with blade in hand towards a Vampire Spawn who was quickly approaching. The party looked on in shock as the two clashed and not one, but two bites were exchanged.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In the end, the Vampires were felled and the Svirfneblin were saved.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The adventurers continued on their way to Tyrybblyn.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Upon arrival, they were led to the headquarters of House Claddatar and accepted their reward for delivering the treacherous merchant Zim. They also accepted a courier mission, delivering Celestilite schematics to Zethlentyn.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We find our heroes at the Slaughtered Star, preparing for a journey to the surface.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The fireworks began when Jer’amy sent a couple green blasts towards a group of zombies and vampires who were out for the blood of a Svirfneblin caravan. Sanzac laid down the mighty moonbeam, while Aldon heated things up. Dreggard spawned an expanse of poky scratchies, and on top of it all, Westin stood ready to unleash a makeshift battering ram. The zombies blazed forward into the fray while the vampires climbed around walls covered with flaming spiderwebs. Those who were lucky enough to advance through the obstacles were pelted by darts and bolts. An ancient Vampire managed to close in on Jer’amy and grab hold of his wrinkly flesh, but in a flash, Jer’amy popped out of harm’s way. Without a victim to feed upon, the vampire tried to flee, but was trapped by the moonbeam and destroyed with a stake to the heart. At this point, Westin rushed in with blade in hand towards a Vampire Spawn who was quickly approaching. The party looked on in shock as the two clashed and not one, but two bites were exchanged. In the end, the Vampires were felled and the Svirfneblin were saved. The adventurers continued on their way to Tyrybblyn. Upon arrival, they were led to the headquarters of House Claddatar and accepted their reward for delivering the treacherous merchant Zim. They also accepted a courier mission, delivering Celestilite schematics to Zethlentyn. We find our heroes at the Slaughtered Star, preparing for a journey to the surface.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mystery of Von Zim’s wares</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mystery of Von Zim’s wares" /><published>2020-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/13/mystery-of-von-zim.html">Sanzac led the way back to Zim’s caravan where the party was asked to help investigate some disappearances from Zim’s wares. The crew put on their detective hats and began sniffing for clues.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon began by subtly hinting at the missing items with the Drow while Jer’amy got to know Nora, Aaron and Haleth better. Dreggard found Brendan practicing some martial moves and showed him a few moves of his own.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A lead suspect was yet to emerge, so Aldon decided to take a more direct approach. He searched Dinnozz’s bag while he slept and found the missing items. Zim was alerted and decided to confront the issue.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dinnozz denied all claims and was enraged at the accusation. He drew his blade as the adventurers tried to mediate. Dreggard only exacerbated the issue and became a target for Dinnozz’s frustration.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A battle began and one of the Steeder’s joined the Drow cause, biting deep into Jer’amy’s hindquarters. Heavily outnumbered, the Drow were defeated but not killed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Zim stared on in shock and Jer’amy noticed a hint of guilt in his eyes. Zim confessed that he planted the items in Dinnozz’s bag. Rhys convinced the party to continue on to Tyrybblyn with Zim locked up in a cart.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not long after, voices were heard in the tunnels ahead. A caravan of Svirfneblin were preparing for a vampire attack, they offered their materials to help build up defenses and Dreggard used his knowledge of nature and survival to devise a plan.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Sanzac led the way back to Zim’s caravan where the party was asked to help investigate some disappearances from Zim’s wares. The crew put on their detective hats and began sniffing for clues. Aldon began by subtly hinting at the missing items with the Drow while Jer’amy got to know Nora, Aaron and Haleth better. Dreggard found Brendan practicing some martial moves and showed him a few moves of his own. A lead suspect was yet to emerge, so Aldon decided to take a more direct approach. He searched Dinnozz’s bag while he slept and found the missing items. Zim was alerted and decided to confront the issue. Dinnozz denied all claims and was enraged at the accusation. He drew his blade as the adventurers tried to mediate. Dreggard only exacerbated the issue and became a target for Dinnozz’s frustration. A battle began and one of the Steeder’s joined the Drow cause, biting deep into Jer’amy’s hindquarters. Heavily outnumbered, the Drow were defeated but not killed. Zim stared on in shock and Jer’amy noticed a hint of guilt in his eyes. Zim confessed that he planted the items in Dinnozz’s bag. Rhys convinced the party to continue on to Tyrybblyn with Zim locked up in a cart. Not long after, voices were heard in the tunnels ahead. A caravan of Svirfneblin were preparing for a vampire attack, they offered their materials to help build up defenses and Dreggard used his knowledge of nature and survival to devise a plan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A fledgling Drow in distress</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A fledgling Drow in distress" /><published>2020-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/08/06/fledgling-drow.html">Our epic saga continues with a Drow in distress, stuck in a massive spider web. Zim urged the caravan to move on, but the adventurers found it in their hearts to escort the entangled child to her family.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The distance was not great, but the mission proved to be quite eventful. Jer’amy triggered two glyphs that were set to ward off intruders, while Dreggard found himself slowed by a massive stone golem.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac disarmed the stone golem, aided by a recollection from the young Drow. The party snuck through a room of trickster mushrooms, then the air became cold.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party had stumbled upon a haunted farmhouse where several undead lay in wait. The terrifying visage of a ghost shook the resolve of the mighty challengers, all except Scutters the Unshakeable!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac brought light to the darkness, burning the undead into non-existence. It was then, that a Drow hunting party, on the lookout for their kin, found the heroes.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party peacefully exchanged the Drow child for some well deserved time in a restorative hot springs.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On their return to the main tunnels, they were ambushed by Hobgoblin bandits, demanding Dreggard’s magical battle axe. Sanzac opted for action over diplomacy and created a mighty eruption under their feet.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Soon after, Jer’amy added acid and cold damage to the fold, and howls could be heard from the black pit.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One bandit managed to escape, but not for long.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac hunted him down and after a fierce battle, the heroes emerged victorious, and Westin gained a new coin purse.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Our epic saga continues with a Drow in distress, stuck in a massive spider web. Zim urged the caravan to move on, but the adventurers found it in their hearts to escort the entangled child to her family. The distance was not great, but the mission proved to be quite eventful. Jer’amy triggered two glyphs that were set to ward off intruders, while Dreggard found himself slowed by a massive stone golem. Sanzac disarmed the stone golem, aided by a recollection from the young Drow. The party snuck through a room of trickster mushrooms, then the air became cold. The party had stumbled upon a haunted farmhouse where several undead lay in wait. The terrifying visage of a ghost shook the resolve of the mighty challengers, all except Scutters the Unshakeable! Sanzac brought light to the darkness, burning the undead into non-existence. It was then, that a Drow hunting party, on the lookout for their kin, found the heroes. The party peacefully exchanged the Drow child for some well deserved time in a restorative hot springs. On their return to the main tunnels, they were ambushed by Hobgoblin bandits, demanding Dreggard’s magical battle axe. Sanzac opted for action over diplomacy and created a mighty eruption under their feet. Soon after, Jer’amy added acid and cold damage to the fold, and howls could be heard from the black pit. One bandit managed to escape, but not for long. Sanzac hunted him down and after a fierce battle, the heroes emerged victorious, and Westin gained a new coin purse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Underdark initiates</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Underdark initiates" /><published>2020-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/30/underdark-initiates.html">Bidding farewell to Stoneheim, the group met with Zim and his ‘Von Zeam Team’. They delved deep under the surface and began their journey through the underdark.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy earned the respect of Nora, the she-dwarf, while Aldon had a little fun with the rearguard’s rears. Zim told some stories and morale was high until a faulty wheel slowed the caravan to a halt and Jer’amy felt compelled to investigate a strange energy in a side tunnel.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The tunnel led to a source of ancient magic which caught our courageous friends in a time loop with a delusional mage and a frisky Gynosphinx.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Both physical and mental faculties were strained as the Gynosphinx challenged the party to answer her riddles in order to be allowed to escape.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After successfully answering, the party tried to also negotiate the release of Gunther the mage, but Persemone the sphinx was too attached to him.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Returning to the carts, the party pondered the possibility of time travel and how they could have done things differently in the past.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not long after their return, a pack of Ankhegs ambushed the VZT (Von Zeam Team). Aaron was snatched up in the vicious mandibles of an Ankheg as it began to burrow underground, but Sanzac’s heroics saved his life.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Slightly bloodied, but still on their feet, the caravan rested and once again, felt new powers surging into their bodies.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Bidding farewell to Stoneheim, the group met with Zim and his ‘Von Zeam Team’. They delved deep under the surface and began their journey through the underdark. Jer’amy earned the respect of Nora, the she-dwarf, while Aldon had a little fun with the rearguard’s rears. Zim told some stories and morale was high until a faulty wheel slowed the caravan to a halt and Jer’amy felt compelled to investigate a strange energy in a side tunnel. The tunnel led to a source of ancient magic which caught our courageous friends in a time loop with a delusional mage and a frisky Gynosphinx. Both physical and mental faculties were strained as the Gynosphinx challenged the party to answer her riddles in order to be allowed to escape. After successfully answering, the party tried to also negotiate the release of Gunther the mage, but Persemone the sphinx was too attached to him. Returning to the carts, the party pondered the possibility of time travel and how they could have done things differently in the past. Not long after their return, a pack of Ankhegs ambushed the VZT (Von Zeam Team). Aaron was snatched up in the vicious mandibles of an Ankheg as it began to burrow underground, but Sanzac’s heroics saved his life. Slightly bloodied, but still on their feet, the caravan rested and once again, felt new powers surging into their bodies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slow times at The Leering Dog</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/23/leering-dog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slow times at The Leering Dog" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/07/23/leering-dog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/23/leering-dog.html">Time has passed since the adventurers arrived in Stoneheim. They made quite a splash on their first night, rescuing a local man from a blazing fire and vanquishing a devil and his entourage.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The action slowed down for the next two weeks and this allowed the party to spend time pursuing some of life’s simpler pleasures.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggard and Scutters sought buried treasure in the many dumpsters lining the Stoneheim streets.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy dusted off his scroll writing technique, surprising several guild members with his superior penmanship and efficiency.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon wined and dined the locals under his guise as a diplomat while Sanzac kept a low profile, keeping up with the gossip and news from the patrons of the Leering Dog. He kept his distance from the Noddy Wheel, which he became convinced was rigged.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The time came for the travelers to ramble on, they reflected on this time of peace with fondness, but their dauntless spirits burned with a desire to march on. The Fab Four met on the stoop of the Leering Dog where they were joined by a familiar face.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">Time has passed since the adventurers arrived in Stoneheim. They made quite a splash on their first night, rescuing a local man from a blazing fire and vanquishing a devil and his entourage. The action slowed down for the next two weeks and this allowed the party to spend time pursuing some of life’s simpler pleasures. Dreggard and Scutters sought buried treasure in the many dumpsters lining the Stoneheim streets. Jer’amy dusted off his scroll writing technique, surprising several guild members with his superior penmanship and efficiency. Aldon wined and dined the locals under his guise as a diplomat while Sanzac kept a low profile, keeping up with the gossip and news from the patrons of the Leering Dog. He kept his distance from the Noddy Wheel, which he became convinced was rigged. The time came for the travelers to ramble on, they reflected on this time of peace with fondness, but their dauntless spirits burned with a desire to march on. The Fab Four met on the stoop of the Leering Dog where they were joined by a familiar face.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The mighty Nightscale &amp;amp; flames of Stoneheim</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/16/mighty-nightscale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The mighty Nightscale &amp;amp; flames of Stoneheim" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/07/16/mighty-nightscale</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/16/mighty-nightscale.html">The journey to Stoneheim was shaping up to be a nice walk in the park until darkness swept in from above in the form of Nightscale, the mighty dragon who laid claim to the Stone Tooth.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
She recognized the smell of these adventurers and noted their fear at her appearance. Just as she was about to strike, Syrus offered her information about a very vulnerable town not far away which caused the beast to froth.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
She demanded a tribute from the party so as not to leave empty handed and Dreggard sacrificed a prized gold ring. Pleased, Nightscale took off to the southeast.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On the fifth day, Archie hooted excitedly that the city of Stoneheim was in sight. The party altered their appearances and gained entry through the gates.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Inside the city, Aldon was recognized by a shady Halfling in an alley. The short fellow slipped something into Aldon’s hands before disappearing into the shadows.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party made their way to a modest tavern and proceeded to burn off some stress by drinking and gambling. Jer’amy had the golden touch, while Sanzac couldn’t win a penny.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dreggared continued his legacy of challenging half-orcs to arm wrestling bouts, winning against the local tough guy.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The crew rented rooms at the Dog and slept on beds for the first time in several nights when they were awoken by screams and curses. They hurried outside to find a nearby warehouse in flames.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sanzac began funneling water into the building but it wasn’t enough to douse the entirety which was filled with flammable flour crates. Jumping inside, Jer’amy found himself ambushed by Kobolds who were led by a demon!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The battle and the fires raged furiously. Jer’amy fell to a fire blast from the fiend but rose back up with the aid of Dreggard’s great berries. Jer’amy returned fire at the devil and his blast hit the bullseye, cracking several devil ribs.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Aldon peppered the room with errant arrows from the outside of the building, and then rushed in through the door piercing the devil through the chest.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jer’amy discovered a captive who was trapped in a room to the north. He blasted open the door and rushed through a flame wall, grabbing onto the frightened man and teleporting him to safety.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The people of Stoneheim cheered as the flames were doused and our heroes emerged victoriously.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">The journey to Stoneheim was shaping up to be a nice walk in the park until darkness swept in from above in the form of Nightscale, the mighty dragon who laid claim to the Stone Tooth. She recognized the smell of these adventurers and noted their fear at her appearance. Just as she was about to strike, Syrus offered her information about a very vulnerable town not far away which caused the beast to froth. She demanded a tribute from the party so as not to leave empty handed and Dreggard sacrificed a prized gold ring. Pleased, Nightscale took off to the southeast. On the fifth day, Archie hooted excitedly that the city of Stoneheim was in sight. The party altered their appearances and gained entry through the gates. Inside the city, Aldon was recognized by a shady Halfling in an alley. The short fellow slipped something into Aldon’s hands before disappearing into the shadows. The party made their way to a modest tavern and proceeded to burn off some stress by drinking and gambling. Jer’amy had the golden touch, while Sanzac couldn’t win a penny. Dreggared continued his legacy of challenging half-orcs to arm wrestling bouts, winning against the local tough guy. The crew rented rooms at the Dog and slept on beds for the first time in several nights when they were awoken by screams and curses. They hurried outside to find a nearby warehouse in flames. Sanzac began funneling water into the building but it wasn’t enough to douse the entirety which was filled with flammable flour crates. Jumping inside, Jer’amy found himself ambushed by Kobolds who were led by a demon! The battle and the fires raged furiously. Jer’amy fell to a fire blast from the fiend but rose back up with the aid of Dreggard’s great berries. Jer’amy returned fire at the devil and his blast hit the bullseye, cracking several devil ribs. Aldon peppered the room with errant arrows from the outside of the building, and then rushed in through the door piercing the devil through the chest. Jer’amy discovered a captive who was trapped in a room to the north. He blasted open the door and rushed through a flame wall, grabbing onto the frightened man and teleporting him to safety. The people of Stoneheim cheered as the flames were doused and our heroes emerged victoriously.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A ghost from Syrus’ past</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/09/ghost-from-syrus-past.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A ghost from Syrus’ past" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/07/09/ghost-from-syrus-past</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/07/09/ghost-from-syrus-past.html">As the lumber camp liberators pondered their next steps, they were joined by Tadriel, who entreated them to join her at a safe place so they could talk. They arrived at a tavern nestled deep in the woods.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The party learned of Tadriel’s cause and history over a couple of rounds of irresistible liqueur. These moments of tranquility did not last long, as ghosts from Syrus’ past appeared and goaded the party into a brawl.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Syrus made an electrifying exit and Sanzac drew his blade. Scutters, in his element, unleashed a fury of bites, dropping several of the antagonists to the ground.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Archie swooped in from above, dropping his payload on the Half-Orc that had made Syrus’ childhood a living hell.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The leader of the thugs surrendered and fled, nearly running straight into Syrus who was waiting outside. Syrus, tired of the senseless violence, let his adversary flee. Tadriel departed for the Kingdom of Celene, offering further work and rewards there.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Eldrin learned of several routes to Celene from a local, while Sanzac poured his heart (and some Sugar Sap) out to a thirsty snake. The decision was made to travel to Stoneheim and seek transport to Celene.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The next day the team set off and marched for nearly 20 hours straight! As they settled down to recuperate, a Mind Flayer and his minions were drawn to their campfire.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Syrus, Dreggard and Scutters were dispatched by a psychic blast from their foe, but by a combined effort from Sanzac and Eldrin, the monster was vanquished.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After a very long day, the adventurers collapsed on their bedrolls and slept like logs.</content><author><name>Dungeon Master</name></author><summary type="html">As the lumber camp liberators pondered their next steps, they were joined by Tadriel, who entreated them to join her at a safe place so they could talk. They arrived at a tavern nestled deep in the woods. The party learned of Tadriel’s cause and history over a couple of rounds of irresistible liqueur. These moments of tranquility did not last long, as ghosts from Syrus’ past appeared and goaded the party into a brawl. Syrus made an electrifying exit and Sanzac drew his blade. Scutters, in his element, unleashed a fury of bites, dropping several of the antagonists to the ground. Archie swooped in from above, dropping his payload on the Half-Orc that had made Syrus’ childhood a living hell. The leader of the thugs surrendered and fled, nearly running straight into Syrus who was waiting outside. Syrus, tired of the senseless violence, let his adversary flee. Tadriel departed for the Kingdom of Celene, offering further work and rewards there. Eldrin learned of several routes to Celene from a local, while Sanzac poured his heart (and some Sugar Sap) out to a thirsty snake. The decision was made to travel to Stoneheim and seek transport to Celene. The next day the team set off and marched for nearly 20 hours straight! As they settled down to recuperate, a Mind Flayer and his minions were drawn to their campfire. Syrus, Dreggard and Scutters were dispatched by a psychic blast from their foe, but by a combined effort from Sanzac and Eldrin, the monster was vanquished. After a very long day, the adventurers collapsed on their bedrolls and slept like logs.</summary></entry></feed>