<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/flanaess-fables/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/flanaess-fables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-29T17:01:19-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Flanaess Fables | Adventures of wandering Oerthlings</title><subtitle>Welcome Oerthlings! Follow the story of our wandering Oerthlings as they adventure across the Flanaess.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ulfe &amp;amp; the horny she-orcs</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/28/ulfe-and-the-she-orcs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ulfe &amp;amp; the horny she-orcs" /><published>2020-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/05/28/ulfe-and-the-she-orcs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/28/ulfe-and-the-she-orcs.html">&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Blasingdell Bunch attempted to take a rest in the Orc bunk room but were interrupted by an Ogre named Great Ulfe who came to exact vengeance on them for murdering his Orc followers. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

        He released his two pet Dire Wolves on the adventurers and they took a barrage of attacks while Ulfe worked his way through a barrier of Orc bodies the party had heaped in the doorway. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        Ulfe slashed Sanzac’s bear form to pieces but was defeated by a well placed arrow from Eldrin. Four more Orcs stormed into the room and took advantage of the intruder’s fatigue, swinging axes and shoving Dreggard to the ground. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        Blasts from Syrus and Eldrin in the back of the room overwhelmed the brutes and they fell to their death one by one. Eldrin took care to set an illusionary fire blockade in front of the bunk room so our heroes could get a full night’s rest. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        When they awoke, they looted several rooms and were able to secure one of Durgeddin’s legendary weapons. Eldrin also secured a magical rapier which he happily added to his arsenal. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        The team worked their way to the grand stair where they discovered a fire trap on one side and a group of horny she-orcs. Sanzac wisely fought fire with fire and the leader’s fiery lust was quelled by a visceral sensation as she cooked inside her ring mail armor. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        One of the leader’s bodyguards figuratively and literally fell for Dreggard. She spent most of the battle chasing him and smiting him with her love. Scutters, Syrus and Dreggard all fell to the floor, unconscious, as a result of her ferocity, but Juliet finally succumbed to an eternal rest after another crack shot from Eldrin’s longbow. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        After all the excitement, and some more looting, the victors rested in the Orc quarters, during the rest, Dreggard couldn’t help admiring the scar on his left arm and thinking wistfully about what might have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Blasingdell Bunch attempted to take a rest in the Orc bunk room but were interrupted by an Ogre named Great Ulfe who came to exact vengeance on them for murdering his Orc followers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">At the gates of Stone Tooth</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/21/gates-of-stone-tooth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At the gates of Stone Tooth" /><published>2020-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/05/21/gates-of-stone-tooth</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/21/gates-of-stone-tooth.html">&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The adventurers slew two Orc scouts and made their way towards the Mountain Door. They snuck by a group of hidden archers and thinking themselves in the clear, casted a minor illusion which alerted the stronghold to their presence. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

        Sanzac and Syrus flexed their spellpower, penetrating the archers behind their cover. Dreggard sent his beast companion dashing across a precarious rope bridge to the great dismay of insectophiles everywhere. Syrus decided to use a little more caution and strung an additional rope along the bridge. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        All characters made it across with minor setbacks. Our heroes discovered two prisoners, Gerry &amp; Coura. They offered them nourishment and helped them to the entrance of the Mountain Door. Dreggard decided they would be fine to travel on their own back to their settlement. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        The party spent the next hour exploring the area, scavenging what they could find. They blasted through a blockade with a blast or two from Syrus’ otherworldly powers. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        After that they discovered another room full of Orcs and laid hunting traps to ambush them. The leader was ensnared and savagely bombarded by Eldrin and Dreggard until he fell to the floor senseless. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        The orcs flailed on Syrus, causing him to retreat around a corner where an Orc with a longbow tried to finish him off. In the end, all the orcs were eliminated. Dreggard and Eldrin discovered an ancient dwarven trap disguised as a stone statue of a mighty warrior. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        Dreggard became poisoned. Sanzac, in bear form, rammed into a nearby doorway he discovered south of the Orc bunkroom. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        
        It bellowed but did not open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The adventurers slew two Orc scouts and made their way towards the Mountain Door. They snuck by a group of hidden archers and thinking themselves in the clear, casted a minor illusion which alerted the stronghold to their presence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The path to Stone Tooth</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/14/path-to-stone-tooth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The path to Stone Tooth" /><published>2020-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/05/14/path-to-stone-tooth</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/14/path-to-stone-tooth.html">&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        You’ve traveled through the forests north of Blasingdell and discovered the base of The Stone Tooth. It’s currently 6:30p on the third day since you set out. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

A swift and fierce storm rolled through earlier in the day, Sanzac avoided exhaustion by shapeshifting into a tiger, Eldrin started feeling slightly fatigued after the storm dissipated. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

You’ve scouted two different paths, one that leads north to steep switchbacks that seem to lead to the mountaintop. The other leads to two Orc scouts who don’t appear to be taking their scouting duties very seriously. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

You are 60ft away from the Orcs and they haven’t noticed your presence.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ve traveled through the forests north of Blasingdell and discovered the base of The Stone Tooth. It’s currently 6:30p on the third day since you set out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A letter from the Baron</title><link href="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/07/letter-from-the-baron.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A letter from the Baron" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/flanaess-fables/2020/05/07/letter-from-the-baron</id><content type="html" xml:base="/flanaess-fables/2020/05/07/letter-from-the-baron.html">&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/baron-map.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Greetings Adventurer,&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Word of thy exploits has reached my ears and I must say, I&apos;m impressed by what you have accomplished thus far. I also have dabbled in adventuring, but raising seven children has greatly inhibited my ability to leave town for long periods of time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

The citizens of Blasingdell all share a keen interest in fine weaponry, and local legend has it that the great dwarf smith Durgeddin the Black once held a stronghold called Khundrukar not far from our town, underneath The Stone Tooth, a rugged, forested hill crowned by a bare, rocky crag. If I have calculated it correctly, it should be about three days journey North from our walls. I&apos;m paying 20 gold for information about the area and 100 gold for a map of the stronghold.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

In addition, I will purchase any weapon you find bearing Durgeddin&apos;s mark for two times the market value! Dwarves are cunning folk, and I would wager there are lavish treasures that lie undiscovered in the depths of Khundrukar.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

If I have judged thee correctly, this information should light a spark in thy chest. Come see me in Blasingdell and I will show you the mark of Durgeddin and answer any questions you may have.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

May Ulaa protect us all,&lt;br&gt;
Baron Althon
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Greetings Adventurer,</summary></entry></feed>